现在我们要为我的机器人添加第三个链接。
Now we are going to add a third link to my robot.
所以现在，我们有一个3自由度机器人，有3个旋转关节或3个旋转关节。
So now, we have a 3-degree of freedom robot with 3 revolute or 3 rotational joints.
该机器人具有更大的工作体积。
This robot has a much larger working volume.
它可以到达这个非常大的圆圈内的任何一点，但因为它有3度
It can reach any point within this very large circle here, but because it has got 3 degrees
自由意味着它不仅可以到达其工作空间内的任何特定位置。
of freedom it means it cannot only reach any particular position within its work space.
它还可以在该特定位置实现任何方向。
It can also achieve any orientation at that particular position.
例如，如果机器人的末端执行器位置在这里，则机器人具有3度
If for example the robot's end effector position is here, then the robot with 3 degrees of
自由能够实现机器人最后一个链接的任何仲裁方向。
freedom is able to achieve any arbitrate orientation of this last link of the robot.
我们可以看到我可以通过该链接和它的相当大范围的角度移动它
We could see I can move it through quite a large range of angles of that link and it
是可能的，因为它有1个额外的自由度。
is possible because it has 1 extra degree of freedom.
让我们确定我们的3连杆机器人的末端执行器的姿势。
Let us determine the pose of the end effector of our 3-link robot.
我们要做的第一件事是注释机器人并引入机器人的长度
The first thing we are going to do is to annotate the robot and introduce the lengths of the
各种链接然后我们将介绍各种关节角度。
various links and then we are going to introduce the various joint angles.
该图中的Q1和Q2均为正，而Q3为负值。
Q1 and Q2 in this diagram are both positive and Q3 here is a negative value.
您注意到旋转方向与Q1和Q2的旋转方向相反。
You note that the direction of rotation is the opposite of that for Q1 and Q2.
当我们为1和2联合机器人做这个时，我展示了坐标系的动画
When we did this for the 1 and 2 joint robots, I showed an animation of the coordinate frame
沿着链接从参考坐标系移动并最终到达末端效应器。
moving from the reference coordinate frame along the links and ending up at the end effector.
这次我不打算做那个动画。
I am not going to do that animation this time.
我认为你有了一般的想法，我们要做的就是写下来
I think you got the general idea and what we are going to do is just write down the
通过检查转换表达。
transform expression by inspection.
我们要做的第一件事是在Q1处旋转它，在X方向上平移
The 1st thing we are going to do is to rotate it at Q1, translate in the X-direction by
A1，以角度Q2旋转，沿X方向沿第二连杆平移量
A1, rotate by the angle Q2, translate along the 2nd link in its X-direction by the amount
然后旋转角度Q3，然后沿X方向平移一个量
of A2 and then rotate by the angle Q3 and then translate in the X-direction by an amount
A3。
A3.
再一次，我可以扩展这些矩阵并将它们相乘以得出它们
Once again, I can expand out what these matrices and multiply them together to come up with
一个均匀的变换，代表这个3关节的末端执行器的姿势
a homogenous transformation which represents the pose of the end effector of this 3-joint
机器人。
robot.
为3连杆机器人手动完成这一点有点单调乏味。
To do this by hand for the 3-link robot is a little bit tedious.
我可能会犯一个错误。
I might make an error.
所以我们将直接进入MATLAB并在那里完成。
So we are going to go straight to MATLAB and do it there.
现在，我们将使用MATLAB来计算这个3链路末端效应器的姿态
Now, we are going to use the MATLAB to compute the pose of the end effector of this 3-link
平面机器人。
planar robot.
这次我们将以符号形式进行。
We are going to do it just in symbolic form this time.
我创建了一些符号来表示3个链接长度：A1，A2和A3，它们代表
I create some symbols to represent the 3 links lengths: A1, A2 and A3 and they represent
3个关节角度：Q1，Q2和Q3。
the 3 joint angles: Q1, Q2 and Q3.
再次，我们使用trchain2来运行，现在我传入的字符串描述了
Once again, we used the trchain2 to function and the string now I pass in describes the
坐标框架从机器人底部移动到尖端的方式。
way the coordinate frame moves from the base of the robot to the tip.
所以我要按角度Q1进行旋转，平移距离A1，旋转
So I am going to do a rotation by the angle Q1, translation by the distance A1, a rotation
通过角度Q2，在X方向上平移距离A2，另一次旋转
by angle Q2, translation in the X-direction by the distance A2, another rotation this
一个是角度Q3，另一个是沿着距离A3移动的距离
one by the angle Q3 and another translation by the distance A3 that is moving along the
机器人的第3个环节。
3rd link of the robot.
现在，我将通过关节角度Q1，Q2和Q3的末端效应器，在这里，我们
Now, I am going to pass the end effector of the joint angles Q1, Q2 and Q3 and here, we
有一个符号表达式，代表这个3连接的末端效应器的姿势
have a symbolic expression which represents the pose of the end effector of this 3-link
机器人。
robot.
你看，这是一个非常复杂的表达，因为我们需要侧向滚动才能看到结束
You see this is now quite a complex expression as we need to scroll sideways to see the end
它的。
of it.
例如，x分量由结果的第1行和第3列给出
The x component for example is given by the 1st row and the 3rd column of the result that
我刚刚计算出来，这是最终效应器的X坐标的表达式
I just computed and that is the expression for the X-coordinate of the end effector of
3连杆机器人。
the 3-link robot.
我还可以导入平面三连杆机器人的模型，这是工具箱功能和
I can also import a model of a planar 3-link robot and that is the tool box function and
平面树在我们的工作区中创建一个串行链接对象。
the planar tree creates a serial link object in our workspace.
该变量称为P3，并且我可以将一些方法应用于此对象
The variable is called P3 and there is some methods that I can apply to this object and
我们之前看过的教学方法。
the teach method that we have looked at previously.
我可以在这个3连杆机器人上做到这一点。
I can do it on this 3-link robot and here it is.
我可以增加1号关节角度。
I can increase joint angle number 1.
我可以减少关节角度2。
I can decrease joint angle number 2.
我可以增加3号关节角度，我们可以看到它移动，我们可以看到位置
I can increase joint angle number 3 and we can see it moving and we can see the position
当我调整这些滑块时，末端执行器的变化。
of the end effector changing as I adjust these sliders.